New York, NY

William Hubenschmidt

https://hubenschmidt.github.io

whubenschmidt@gmail.com mobile: 347-909-0064

ABOUT ME

Full-stack developer and audio engineer. After seven years in the nonprofit sector, I chose to elevate my career as a software developer.

Strong creative background, and experience in database design, implementation, and management. Ten years experience in sales and fundraising roles. Specialties include JavaScript, Node/Express, React, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Github, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Salesforce, and proposal writing.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer, Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp, New York, NY

■ A 26-week immersive course in full-stack software development.

99¢ Dreams Records, 99¢ Radio, New York, NY

Executive Producer & Audio Engineer, August 2010-present

- Audio production; imagine and execute sound design; lead projects from development to execution; specialize in vinyl record and cassette production and dance music sales reaching international audiences in Europe and Japan, achieving airplay on BBC Radio 1 Essential Mix.
- Live stream internet radio and digital content management including design and code of www.99centradio.com; HD video encoding and high quality audio streaming; social media and streaming audio service integration
- Event production; booking, promoting, and executing local events featuring house and electronic music artists.

Nonprofit Fundraising Technology, New York, NY

Consultant, January 2013-March 2016

- CRM database, web development, and fundraising for small business and mid-sized nonprofit clients including the Correctional Association of New York, Japan Society, James & Company, Color + Information, and Creative Connections, LLC.
- Co-authored "Why Every Nonprofit Needs CRM and How to Get it Right", a paper on best practices in database management and implementation in the nonprofit sector, published by Salsa (www.salsalabs.com).

Amnesty International USA, New York, NY

Development Associate—Office of the Executive Director, June 2012-January 2013

Robert F. Kennedy Center for Justice and Human Rights, New York, NY

Database Administrator, May 2011-June 2012

- Database management: implemented and managed Salesforce.com database for three international offices.
- Co-launched RFK Young Leaders, a young professionals' network to empower human rights activists and defenders; managed outreach, volunteer, and fundraising activities. Managed event productions featuring Q-Tip (2012) and Questlove (2013) to raise more than \$100,000 for human rights education project.

AmeriCorps VISTA, Austin, TX and New York, NY
Grant Writer and Database Analyst, April 2009-May 2011

EDUCATION

Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp, Columbia University, New York, NY, 2019 – Full Stack Web Development **University of Michigan**, Ann Arbor, MI, 2008 – B.A., American Culture/Music